Ahmed M. Ibrahim El-bastawisi

Senior Software Engineer · Mansoura, Egypt

<u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>GitHub</u>

+20 1013162775 · ahmedbastawisi@outlook.com

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology sector. Skilled full stack .NET developer. Strong engineering professional with a bachelor's degree focused on Computer Science from Computer Engineering and Systems, Mansoura University.

Technical Skills

C#, ASP.NET Core MVC, Entity Framework Core, SQL, SignalR, Webrtc, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Angular

Achievements

- **Graduation Project:** Autonomous Car System, navigate complex environments switching between different behaviors (go to goal, avoid obstacles, follow wall)
- Responsibilities: Design and test different algorithms using Matlab based Simulator (Sim.Lam)
- Graduation Project Grade: Distinction
- Udacity Advanced Web Development Nanodegree (October, 2020)

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

DSQUARES · Full-time

Aug 2023 - Present · Cairo, Egypt

Developing new features and redesigning existing modules of dsquares loyalty products to be more scalable and efficient.

- Plan, design, develop, debug, implement and support web-based software applications and services.
- Improve software quality by conducting systems analysis and recommending changes in policies and procedures.
- Produce detailed software design and specifications.
- Participate in planning for software development sprints, and ensure tasks are completed according to the planned delivery dates.
- Represent the team in collaborations with partners and clients as needed.

Software Engineer

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE Co. W.L.L · Full-time Jan 2018 – May 2023 · Cairo, Egypt

Develop and maintain ERP web-based SaaS Application.

- Design a web-based enterprise resource planning software
- Improving system quality by identifying issues and common patterns
- Track issues and fix bugs
- Deploying product updates

Education

Computer Engineering and Systems, Mansoura University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering, 2012 – 2017

Cumulative Grade: 72.15 % (good)

Personal Skills

- Hard-working, Minute to Detail
- High-level of maturity and sense of responsibility
- Sound time management skills
- Ability to work in a team driven environment

Languages

- Arabic (Native proficiency)
- English (Professional working proficiency)

Personal Information

• Birth Date: August 1, 1994

• Marital Status: Single

• Military Status: Exempted